Did you
notice how John
handled this situation?
He acknowledged
the impact of the delay
without becoming defensive.
He then voiced his own need
for clearer priorities,
and, crucially,
he invited Anna to work
together on a solution.
This is assertive
communication and action.
The tone is calm,
the words are clear,
and the message respects
both John's
perspective and Anna's.
The result?
Tension decreases,
trust increases,
and the meeting
becomes constructive.
Assertiveness doesn't mean
being louder or pushing harder.
It means balancing firmness
with respect.
When you do this, you
not only protect your own needs,
you also strengthen collaboration.
How do you think
Anna perceived John
in this exchange
as a problem maker
or as a problem solver?